http://www.javaspecialists.co.za/about/privacy.jsp

Javaspecialists
Running on Java 16-ea+26-1764 (Preview)
Self-Study Courses
Data Structures in Java 9 ($250)
Java Design Patterns Course ($525)
Java Concurrency in Practice Bundle ($900)
Java Specialists Superpack 2020 ($1870)
More...
Responsible For Data Protection and Privacy
The responsible entity from the perspective of the EU privacy
law and national privacy laws of the member states and other
privacy related regulations is:
The GPDR currently does not require us to name a privacy
officer. For that reason the CEO of the company is responsible.
You can contact the CEO under the address mentioned above.
General aspects
Extend of processing of personal data
We only process personal data, when it is required to serve
our website, our services or other content. Personal data will
only be processed when the user agreed to it. An exception
will be made if a consent could not be given in advance and
the law allows processing in this case.
Deletion of data and storage duration
Personal data will be deleted or access denied, when there is
no reason to store it anymore.
It can still be stored, when
the law requires us to.
Serving Our Websites
Description and Extend of Data Procession
We do not use analytics tools like Google Analytics.
Apache Webserver creates logfiles containing your IP address.
It also logs what files you have requested from us.
We do not store log data together with other personal data of
the user.
Reasons for processing this data
We use the IP address of the user to send websites and
content to the users. Information about it is stored to
avoid abuse of others, find problems and improve our service
in general.
Dissent and removal
We need to write log files to provide our service. There is
no possibility for dissent and we cannot remove your data.
If there is an urgent matter in this case, please send us a
message to privacy@javaspecialists.eu.
Use of cookies
We do not use any cookies on www.javaspecialists.eu.
Subdomains, such as javaspecialists.teachable.com, run on the
Teachable platform and use cookies.
Please see the
privacy
policy for Teachable for the subdomain.
Comments on our website
We are using Disqus to enable our users to leave comments on
our website. Disqus is a service provided in the USA. You can
read the privacy statement of Disqus here: Link.
Comments will only be loaded when the user presses a button.
Unless he gives consent to this, no connection to Disqus will
be enabled.
Newsletter, Slack and Enquiries
Description and extend of data procession
We send newsletters to our users when they subscribed to it
as well as occasional promotional emails about Java education,
such as courses and conferences.
Newsletters are free of charge. We use the service "Infusionsoft".
For subscription we forward to the web pages of Infusionsoft.
You can read the privacy statement of Infusionsoft here: Link.
To send you newsletters, we will ask for your e-mail address,
your first name and your Java skill level.
We also ask for
your last name and your country, but the response is not
mandatory to receive the newsletters.
Links in newsletters are redirected to Infusionsoft, which
may set tags to track interest.
The tags may also be used
to start campaign sequences.
For enquiry forms regarding our courses or consulting or
general enquiries, we request your phone number and company
in order to be able to evaluate your request and to respond
in a quick and efficient manner.
We also log your IP address
together with your enquiry to confirm the country you are
enquiring from.
An example of such an enquiry form can be
seen here.
We offer a free Slack channel for Java enthusiasts.
To
register we need to ask your first and last name, as well as
email address.
This information is sent to Slack to
register you.
Please read the Slack privacy policy here:
Slack Privacy Policy.
Reasons for processing
Your data will be used to send newsletters to you as well
as relevant commercial offers by the publishers of the
newsletter.
Dissent and removal
The subscription can be cancelled at any time. Every newsletter
contains a link at the bottom that can be used for that.
Rights of the affected person
Right for disclosure
You can ask for a confirmation if we store any personal data of yours. If we do, you can ask for further information:
Why we store your data
The kind of data, which we process
The recipients of your data, including those, who will receive your data in future
All information available of how we got your data
You also have the right for disclosure to whom we send your data (organisations and third countries).
Please contact us here.
Right for correction
You have the right to get your data corrected if it is wrong or not complete. The correction will be done as soon as possible.
Please contact us here.
Right for deletion
You can ask for the deletion of your data.
Please
contact us here.
Right for complaints to regulators
You have the right to complain to regulators if you are in the opinion we process data of yours illegally. The regulators will keep you informed about your case.
Services we are using
As you have the right to learn where your data might end up we compiled you a list of software we are using in our business.
We use:
Dropbox for exchanging documents
Backblaze for backing up our computer systems
Infusionsoft as a CRM and to send newsletters
Deadline Funnel for managing promotions
GoToWebinar for hosting webinars
Skype for business communication
Slack for our community discussion group
GitHub to host our software source code, to work on issues and do project management
Teachable to host our online self-study training: Teachable Privacy Policy
Google G-Suite for our email, calendar, Google Groups, and document sharing
Hetzner for hosting our root server
Zapier for integrating between the different platforms
Bonjoro for sending video messages
Subscribe Now
Get: every new article, exclusive invites to live webinars, our top-10 articles ever, access to expert tutorials & more!
CountrySPAMMER HoneypotAfghanistanAlbaniaAlgeriaAmerican SamoaAndorraAngolaAnguillaAntarcticaAntigua and BarbudaArgentinaArmeniaArubaAustraliaAustriaÅland IslandsAzerbaijanBahamasBahrainBangladeshBarbadosBelarusBelgiumBelizeBeninBermudaBhutanBoliviaBosnia and HerzegovinaBotswanaBouvet IslandBrazilBritish Indian Ocean TerritoryBrunei DarussalamBulgariaBurkina FasoBurundiCambodiaCameroonCanadaCape VerdeCayman IslandsCentral African RepublicChadChileChinaChristmas IslandCocos (Keeling) IslandsColombiaComorosCongoDemocratic Republic Of CongoCook IslandsCosta RicaCroatiaCubaCuraçaoCyprusCzech RepublicCôte D'IvoireDenmarkDjiboutiDominicaDominican RepublicEcuadorEgyptEl SalvadorEquatorial GuineaEritreaEstoniaEthiopiaFalkland IslandsFaroe IslandsFijiFinlandFranceFrench GuianaFrench PolynesiaFrench Southern TerritoriesGabonGambiaGeorgiaGermanyGhanaGibraltarGreeceGreenlandGrenadaGuadeloupeGuamGuatemalaGuernseyGuineaGuinea-BissauGuyanaHaitiHeard and McDonald IslandsHoly See (Vatican City State)HondurasHong KongHungaryIcelandIndiaIndonesiaIranIraqIrelandIsle of ManIsraelItalyJamaicaJapanJerseyJordanKazakhstanKenyaKiribatiNorth KoreaSouth KoreaKuwaitKyrgyzstanLaosLatviaSPAMMER HoneypotSPAMMER HoneypotLebanonLesothoLiberiaLibyaLiechtensteinLithuaniaLuxembourgMacaoRepublic of MacedoniaMadagascarMalawiMalaysiaMaldivesMaliMaltaMarshall IslandsMartiniqueMauritaniaMauritiusMayotteMexicoFederated States of MicronesiaMoldovaMonacoMongoliaMontenegroMontserratMoroccoMozambiqueMyanmarNamibiaNauruNepalNetherlandsNew CaledoniaNew ZealandNicaraguaNigerNigeriaNiueNorfolk IslandNorthern Mariana IslandsNorwayOmanPakistanPalauPalestinePanamaPapua New GuineaParaguayPeruPhilippinesPitcairnPolandPortugalPuerto RicoQatarRomaniaRussian FederationRwandaRéunionSt. BarthélemySt. Helena, Ascension and Tristan Da CunhaSt. Kitts And NevisSt. LuciaSt. MartinSt.
Pierre And MiquelonSt. Vincent And The GrenedinesSamoaSan MarinoSao Tome and PrincipeSaudi ArabiaSenegalSerbiaSeychellesSierra LeoneSingaporeSlovakiaSloveniaSolomon IslandsSomaliaSouth AfricaSouth Georgia and the South Sandwich IslandsSpainSri LankaSudanSurinameSvalbard And Jan MayenSwazilandSwedenSwitzerlandSyrian Arab RepublicTaiwanTajikistanTanzaniaThailandTimor-LesteTogoTokelauTongaTrinidad and TobagoTunisiaTurkeyTurkmenistanTurks and Caicos IslandsTuvaluUgandaUkraineUnited Arab EmiratesUnited KingdomUnited StatesUS Minor Outlying IslandsUruguayUzbekistanVanuatuVenezuelaViet NamVirgin Islands, BritishVirgin Islands, U.S.Wallis and FutunaWestern SaharaYemenZambiaZimbabweSPAMMER Honeypot
Java Skill Level *BeginnerIntermediateAdvancedGuru
Agree to JavaSpecialists Privacy Policy *
Subscribe
Read our Privacy Policy
Java Training
We deliver relevant courses, by top Java developers to produce more
resourceful and efficient programmers within their organisations.
Java Training
Java Consulting
We can help make your Java application run faster and
trouble-shoot concurrency and performance bugs...
Java Consulting
Java Emergency?
If your system is down, we will review it for 15 minutes
and give you our findings for just 1 € without any
obligation.
Get Help Now
286Discernment on the Shoulders of Giants
Today is the 20th anniversary of The Java Specialists' Newsletter. Time to sit back, relax, grab a coffee and wax lyr... Full Article
285I/O Stream Memory Overhead
Each PrintStream uses about 25kb of memory. This might seem reasonable if we only have System.out and System.err. But... Full Article
284java.util.PrimitiveIterator.OfInt
Java 8 Streams were the first time that Java deliberately split utility classes into multiple versions to be used for... Full Article
283Four Billion Changes
A nice puzzle to brighten your day - how can we make the Iterator think that the List has not been changed? Full Article
282Biased locking a goner, but better things Loom ...
Biased locking has made unnecessary mutexes cheap for over a decade. However, it is disabled by default in Java 15, s... Full Article
281Puzzle 2: Is it garbage?
In our next puzzle, we up the ante a bit. We prevent GC during the test() method by storing a strong reference to all... Full Article
JavaSpecialists
We deliver relevant courses, by top Java developers to produce more resourceful and efficient
programmers within their organisations. Find Out More
Quick Links
Home
The Newsletter
Java Training
About Us
Java Consulting
Connect With Us
Follow Heinz on Twitter
Join the Facebook Group
Drop Heinz an Email
Contact Us Page
Copyright © 2000-2020 Dr Heinz Kabutz - All Rights Reserved.
•
All Rights Reserved. •
Website design and build
Catch22 Marketing • Sitemap
Oracle and Java are registered trademarks of Oracle and/or its affiliates. Other names may be trademarks of their respective owners. JavaSpecialists.eu is not connected to Oracle, Inc. and is not sponsored by Oracle, Inc.
